Anasse LAARABI

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER



Contact.laarabi@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with a passion for building intuitive and visually stunning applications. I have a solid foundation in front-end and back-end technologies and enjoy collaborating with cross-functional teams to bring projects from conception to deployment.

My experience includes coding, troubleshooting, and testing. I am also trilingual, speaking English, French, and Arabic.

SKILLS

Front-End: React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 **Back-End:** PHP, Symfony, Node.js, Ruby, Rails,

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

212Communication

Full-Stack Developer

04, 2022 - Present

- → Successfully converted designs into scalable, responsive, multi-platform WordPress websites.
- → Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Symfony to build landing pages and websites.
- → Worked with databases such as MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and NoSQL databases.
- → Integrated and consumed APIs to interact with external services and data sources.
- → Wrote unit tests and debugged code to ensure functionality and identify and fix issues.
- → Handled server deployment and maintenance on platforms.
- → Managed projects effectively, set priorities, and delivered high-quality solutions on time.

09, 2022 - Present

Self-Employed

Freelancer

- → Successfully converted Figma designs into scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO-friendly websites.
- → Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React to build landing pages and websites for events.
- → Optimizing website and web application performance, including page load times and search engine rankings.
- → Continuously researching and staying up-to-date with the latest front-end development technologies, frameworks, and best practices.
- → Delivered exceptional web applications to over 20 satisfied clients.

MICROVERSE

Remote Full-Stack Web Development Student and Mentor

Remote 05, 2022 - 01, 2023

- → Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects both independently and via pair programming.
- → Mentored a group of five junior web developers, and provided technical support to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline.
- → Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- → Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

STAR SAMU

Billing supervisor

Marrakesh, Morocco 11, 2020 - 04, 2022

- → Implemented new and efficient processes for invoicing, payment tracking, and follow-up, which resulted in increased on-time payment rates and increased billing accuracy.
- → Trained and managed a team of two billing specialists who were responsible for sending invoices to clients and collecting payments.

EDUCATION

META

Front-End Developer Professional Certificate

- → Developed expertise in a variety of front-end technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, and learned how to use these technologies to build and maintain responsive and user-friendly websites and web applications.
- → Learned best practices for user experience.

MICROVERSE

Remote Full Stack Web Development Certificate, Full Time

- → Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- → Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.